Eli Cusic

etcusic@gmail.com | 425-622-3450 Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github | Blog

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby and JavaScript based programming as a full stack developer with a background in logistics and staff management. Working in logistics and restaurants helped me develop strong skills in creative problem solving, prioritizing tasks under pressure, and accomplishing goals in a team-oriented environment. I transitioned into software development to apply my passion and talent for designing systems that are efficient, flexible, and intuitive.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technologies: Ruby, Rails, Javascript, React, Redux, SQL, Postgresql, Active Record, HTML, CSS, Materialize,

Omniauth, Sinatra, Git/Github

Methodologies: Full stack development, OOP, MVC design, REST API, TDD

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ESL Exercises & Games - url | repo | demo

Multiple interactive memory games using flash cards in a React single page app with a Rails API backend.

- Used React components to handle view changes throughout application
- Fetched data from a Rails API to get data for learning games
- Created dynamic input form using React tools and logic for the user to customize exercises
- Developed logic for multiple different exercises from scratch using JavaScript including flash card practice, multiple choice, a speed game, bingo, and connect four

Vanilla JS Speed Game - repo | demo

Single page vanilla JS project and Rails API backend. Speed memory game using flash cards.

- Created a memory based game with a timer and scoring system
- Connected to Rails server with fetch requests to send and receive data
- Employed JavaScript logic to manage multiple screen changes during use of the application
- Structured the application in an object oriented way to make it clean, DRY, and well organized
- Used multiple has many/belongs to relationships on the Rails backend

Tutoring App - repo | demo

An online hosting platform between tutors and students where students can book appointments for tutors.

- Used single table inheritance and controller inheritance structure to handle routing for different types of users
- Utilized Active Record validations to handle user verification and authorization
- Implemented Omniauth to allow users to sign in from a Facebook account

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Free Burma Rangers
Director of Logistics
Thailand/Burma
2013 - 2016

- Coordinated the acquisition, transportation, and tracking of supplies to field teams
- Developed and integrated a supply tracking system for the organization
- Created reference materials for how to accomplish common tasks within the logistics department
- Collaborated with field teams and accounting department to prioritize supply acquisition

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Blazing Onion, Kitchen Manager, Mill Creek, WA **Burger Up**, Kitchen Manager, Nashville, TN

2017 - 2018
2010 - 2013

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, Online, Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript 01/2021

Google, Online, IT Support Professional Certificate Program 08/2019

Samford University, Birmingham, AL, Bachelor's Degree in Philosophy 05/2012